hello everybody on this video I'm going
to talk about the two best things that
any junior developer can do to improve
their learning experience their process
and their career as a whole
first thing not only focus on the
technology by this I mean if you just
started learning web development let's
say you're gonna start with HTML then
you're gonna move on to CSS right now
don't only focus there and like I need
to dominate CSS and I'm gonna look
anywhere else learn CSS style CSS but
also start looking into the whole
landscape of web development maybe
Google some words maybe ask friends and
we look into forums maybe just be
curious about how the whole landscape
looks maybe like like for example you
will look at Instagram
how is histogram made so you're going to
Google that and you'll see the jungle
you're like all right so what's jungle
and then you look oh it's a Python thing
Python what's Python oh it's a language
cool I'm not saying go and learn Python
and go and learn Django but at least
learn the landscape of what you just go
into the only focus on CSS learn stuff
learn the outside parts like all the
landscape alright so these will also
help you because then when you know HTML
CSS you might be thinking like actually
I don't I didn't really like this part
of doing design but I read about the
Instagram being built in Jungle so you
know what let me go and get jungle
because now I know what a back-end is so
let's go and learn back it if you didn't
Google and do all the stuff that we said
before you wouldn't know where to go
next and you will just follow this group
that everybody tells you that even I
tell you if you know the landscape you
will be able to play to your strengths
and you will be able to say you know
what I don't know what nodejs is but I
heard it's good for real-time because
Google over runs on know this so I want
to build a real-time game maybe I should
start there probably these knowing the
landscape will help you a lot a lot a
lot a lot because it will make you more
knowledgeable of the area where you are
again you will still be
in CSS and you will start them all and
you will move on slowly but knowing the
landscape and alone knowing what you got
yourself into is very good and this will
help you on the next thing I will
recommend the taken thing is that you
need to go and work for free work for
free I know many people would say you
should never work for free if you're
good at something never do it for free
people don't appreciate free stuff the
blahblah
here if you're just a junior developer
and you have no portfolio whatsoever and
you're gonna go out there and look for a
job and you're gonna go out there and
look for a client it's gonna be harder
then if you had a portfolio and then if
you had some experience so the best
thing you could do for your career will
be to start working for free do stuff
for free do useful stuff for free and
help others on the way I could tell you
you know what just make a toy project
every weekend and after two months
you're going to have eight toy projects
one per week there's gonna be a huge
portfolio maybe that will get you hired
and that's okay you could do that but
also if you go and work for free you
will get experience that not not how a
product can give you if you wanna work
for free that sell you work for your
uncle and he's got some restaurant or
whatever right if you couldn't work for
free you will learn how to maybe
communicate with a client how to
understand the needs of a business how
to understand what to use on this
business if for example you will see
your uncle's business whatever it is and
you see that he is maybe taking
reservations we have phone calls and
then he puts them on an Excel and it's
kind of a little bit too inefficient
then you can say hey you know what I
know how to build websites I'm gonna
make him a reservation taker online so
people can't ever see patients for his
website so I can improve this is more
little part of his business that right
there sets you apart from all the other
developers that are just building stuff
as a toy project why because you just
have your first real life project you
have to come up with something useful
that actually people really need like
your uncle for example and you will also
get into the base
- that requires you when you need to
make a website when you need to
understand the needs of a client and
also you help somebody and also because
it's what is for free those people
wouldn't complain that much I don't know
about I don't know if you have ever said
to anybody hey let me give you this food
for free and they'll be like nah
that if you do the same thing with your
skills and with your code people will
appreciate them people will take them
and since it's a free thing that you've
given them you'll be a learning
experience for both of you
they wouldn't complain that much you
will do the best job you can and it's
gonna be a win-win for everybody
but especially especially for you I know
many people say you shouldn't work for
free because there's an appreciate above
a blood but I really think that that's
exactly what you need to do when you're
starting work for free as you know I
always say you should always learn when
you need to learn you shouldn't learn
just because it's there on the internet
and it's a list of ten you should learn
you should always learn you need to
learn in this case this is the perfect
example you will only need to learn what
the features that you're building I
think that if you combine these two
things you're gonna start and have a
career that's gonna be amazing I wish I
have done this when you when I started I
have I didn't start doing stuff free I
did later on when I was traveling but it
is one of the best ways to get clients
it is one of the best ways to get
experience working with them one of the
best ways to apply knowledge one of the
best ways to make portfolio also you
will make useful things you will help
people be kind to one another like it's
gonna be just an amazing thing and again
don't get too caught up in - no they
should pay me maybe don't get caught up
in that get caught up in I'm gonna help
somebody I'm gonna do something useful I
just learned this code I'm gonna apply
it in a real-life project trust me that
is gonna get you a job either in a
company when you go to the interview and
then interview people tell you what have
you done and you have a real life
project that are already being built and
there are used by people or if your
uncle sees that you're doing a great job
maybe later he will cut his friend and
then you can charge his friend to do
something similar I don't know it's
gonna be like bow snowball is gonna
become bigger and bigger
the more people you help the more people
that want to help you you want to help
you
the more people you would know the more
people you know the more clients you
will get etc is it turn is it thank you
for watching let me know what you think
about this small piece of advice if you
haven't done it let me know how it went
if you think that people shouldn't work
for free then let me know your opinion
and let me know why you think is
shooting work for free maybe you have an
opinion there and I would like to know
that's it for this video give a like
leave a comment don't forget to
subscribe share this with your friends
with your junior friend developers and I
will see you on the next one be kind to
people and eat kimchi alright